<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coala on Meet Mangukiya | My Blog</title>
    <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/tags/coala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coala on Meet Mangukiya | My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license&lt;br&gt;Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io/) with the [Type Theme](//github.com/digitalcraftsman/hugo-type-theme)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 11:56:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meetmangukiya.github.io/tags/coala/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Final week of community bonding at coala</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-final-week-community-bonding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 11:56:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-final-week-community-bonding/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So, the community bonding period has finally come to an end and the coding
phases will start, more fun follows now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already started a bit of coding, I ported some of the plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things done in this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-added-the-dockerfile&#34;&gt;1. Added the Dockerfile.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yukiisbored&#34;&gt;@yukiisbored&lt;/a&gt; created the dockerfile for
   corobo. He is our devops guy at coala, he does the awesome work of
   deploying coala website, webservices, blog, gitmate etc. He is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-the-test-suite-for-the-repo-has-been-set&#34;&gt;2. The test suite for the repo has been set.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests are written in the &lt;code&gt;tests/&lt;/code&gt; directory. Errbot comes with a pytest
   fixture &lt;code&gt;testbot&lt;/code&gt; that can be used in testing. The fixture is working
   pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-start-contributing&#34;&gt;3. Start contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the repository structure is already laid and the test suite has already
   been made, outside contributions on various plugins are highly encouraged,
   for a quick guide headout to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coala/corobo/wiki&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-upstream&#34;&gt;4. Upstream&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some documentation fixes and fixed one wrong assertion upstream in the
   errbot repo. The gitter channel is quite active, it is helpful to have
   support upstream :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-regarding-topic-modeling&#34;&gt;5. Regarding topic modeling:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After recognizing the topic for the question, the next thing is to get
   the answer from the document. This part is what I call &amp;ldquo;Passage
   retrieval&amp;rdquo;. This was a bit difficult one. There are many possible alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can search the documentation with the topic obtained from the question using a search engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use tfidf on the documentation with topic and use the one with the highest score as the appropriate doc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-after-retrieving-the-documentation-other-thing-would-be-linking-to-the&#34;&gt;6. After retrieving the documentation, other thing would be linking to the&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;documentation and ideally summarizing the same. For summarizing we would be
   using the summarizer available in the gensim already.(Most probably,
   subjected to change.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC community bonding week 2</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 21:09:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-week-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;status-update&#34;&gt;Status Update&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-milestones&#34;&gt;Create milestones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started creating milestones for bonding phase and coding phase 1, 2, and 3 and
populating those milestones with issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/2&#34;&gt;Bonding Milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/23&#34;&gt;Coding Phase 1 Milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/24&#34;&gt;Coding Phase 2 Milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/25&#34;&gt;Coding Phase 3 Milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-engine-frameworks-vs-topic-modeling-frameworks&#34;&gt;Search Engine Frameworks VS. Topic Modeling Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started discussing about the auto-responding feature of corobo. We started by
weighing &lt;strong&gt;search engine frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;topic modeling frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;. It was
decided to use topic modeling frameworks instad of any other search engine
frameworks like Solr, Lucene, ElasticSearch, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/issues/3&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/issues/3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-prototype&#34;&gt;Build Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic steps to retrieve the topic/key of the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-process the input text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train over the input documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the trained model to retrieve the topic of the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In prototypes, we try to change the training methods, pre-processing methods to
get as efficient results as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototypes can be found here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/meetmangukiya/topic-modelling-prototype&#34;&gt;https://github.com/meetmangukiya/topic-modelling-prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-repo-structure-and-setup-ci&#34;&gt;Basic repo structure and setup CI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repository for the new cobot is setup at github:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coala/corobo&#34;&gt;https://github.com/coala/corobo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travis CI is setup for the repository. coafile is added to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-writing-a-cep&#34;&gt;Start writing a cEP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started writing a cEP for my GSoC project:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coala/cEPs/pull/77&#34;&gt;https://github.com/coala/cEPs/pull/77&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted for GSoC 2017 at coala</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/accepted-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 07:49:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/accepted-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;accepted-for-gsoc&#34;&gt;Accepted for GSoC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I created a post about me applying for GSoC under coala organization.
And the results were declared on 4th May, and guess what? I am accepted as a
GSoC student!! How awesome is that?! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meetmangukiya.github.io/img/gsoc_email.png&#34; alt=&#34;GSoC Acceptance Email&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-lies-further&#34;&gt;So what lies further&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that the results are out, the next phase is the Community Bonding period.
During this period we are supposed to research more about our project, create
milestones and think about the implementation details; do code reviews, present
our project on coala mailing lists, and work out the schedule to follow in the 3
months of coding period; contact our mentors and discuss the project further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not the usual &amp;ldquo;start implementing right away&amp;rdquo; kinda thing where you just
start coding without thinking about future pitfalls and implementations. So,
this is something new and interesting, because now we program in a more
structured, organized and well planned way; we will already know how we have
to proceed. And also be certain that the achieved product will be a better,
maintainable piece of software and not just a &amp;ldquo;just works&amp;rdquo; ugly kinda software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging weekly from now on summarizing the work done in that week and
work that I might be doing in the subsequent weeks, its gonna be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My project abstract can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/projects/#4913450777051136&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had a video conference with my mentor
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Udayan12167&#34;&gt;Udayan&lt;/a&gt; regarding the projects, where we set
things to do in this week. Most important of all being to find a more viable way
to search and answer user queries from documentation by either using search
engine frameworks or Topic Modelling frameworks. So in this week I&amp;rsquo;ll be
checking out various frameworks and see the pros and cons of each and
accordingly decide one framework that I&amp;rsquo;ll use in the answering-user-query part
of my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now, cy&amp;rsquo;ll next week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Proposal - Debugger for coala bears</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-coala-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 18:15:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-coala-debugger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-am-applying-for-google-summer-of-code&#34;&gt;I am applying for Google Summer of Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-google-summer-of-code-a-k-a-gsoc&#34;&gt;What is Google Summer of Code a.k.a. GSoC?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Summer of Code is a platform to encourage students to work for Open
Source. It is a 3 month internship-like program whereby student works with Open
Source Organizations under the guidance of a mentor
(who is usually a member of the organization) to write/modify programs/softwares
for the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-coala&#34;&gt;What is coala?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;coala is a program that provides a unified interface to statically analyse
any project through one application. It wraps many linters across different
languages and prints results and messages from those linters, and also apply
and suggest patches for the given messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;coala runs all the analyis routines through the bears. Bears are like plugins
and coala is like a framework. Bears are configured through a file &lt;code&gt;.coafile&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;coala runs all the analysis/bears by just running &lt;code&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt;, isn&amp;rsquo;t it just
awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am applying for a GSoC project under &lt;a href=&#34;https://coala.io&#34;&gt;coala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-my-project-about&#34;&gt;What is my project about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debug-and-profile-bears&#34;&gt;Debug and profile bears.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My project is about creating a debugger for coala, to debug the coala bears and
create an interface to profile the bears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debugger&#34;&gt;Debugger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-not-use-pdb&#34;&gt;Why not use pdb?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may ask that one may just use &lt;code&gt;pdb&lt;/code&gt; to debug the bears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing bears in coala is very easy, thanks to its user friendly and abstract
API. But the bear developers, usually find difficulty in debugging the bears.
In bear debugging, the user usually do not need to debug the bear that
&lt;em&gt;low levelly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;debug-modes&#34;&gt;Debug modes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debugger that I&amp;rsquo;ll be creating has three modes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug Mode:
In Debug mode, the debugging is started as it is as in pdb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superficial Mode:
In Superficial mode, the arguments and return values of debugged function
call is captured. This would remove unnecessary stepping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report Mode:
This is probably the most useful mode. If this mode is used, then the bear
is ran and the arguments and the return values of all the subsequent function
calls are captured and printed in a beautiful tabular form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;debugging-environment&#34;&gt;Debugging environment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of importing the bear, instantiate them, and run the bear with requried
setting is a trivial job that can be automated inside coala, so the devs don&amp;rsquo;t
need to set it up on their own ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bear being debugged will be imported. If no settings are provided in the CLI
then settings in the coafile will be used while running the bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;debug&#34;&gt;Debug!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the importing and collecting of settings is done. Its time to start
debugging. The run method of the bear is called in &lt;em&gt;Debug Mode&lt;/em&gt;. After that at
every line, user has an option to do whatever options pdb already has plus the
superficial mode. Superficial mode will perform the function call and print the
arguments and the return value at that line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the report mode. If the report mode flag is set to true, then the run
method of bear is called in superficial mode which will directly print the
&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt; and return values and arguments of all the function calls in the run
 method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;profiler&#34;&gt;Profiler&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the bear is written and debugged, the author may want to check if he can
do any performance improvements in the bear. This is where profiling comes into
the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User can run bear with a &lt;code&gt;--profile&lt;/code&gt; option and a nice profile report will be
created for the given run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More specific info in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://meetmangukiya.github.io/GSoC-DebugandProfileBears-coala.pdf&#34;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
