<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coala on Meet Mangukiya | My Blog</title>
    <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/tags/coala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coala on Meet Mangukiya | My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license&lt;br&gt;Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io/) with the [Type Theme](//github.com/digitalcraftsman/hugo-type-theme)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 07:49:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://meetmangukiya.github.io/tags/coala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted for GSoC 2017 at coala</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/accepted-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 07:49:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/accepted-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Accepted for GSoC Last month I created a post about me applying for GSoC under coala organization. And the results were declared on 4th May, and guess what? I am accepted as a GSoC student!! How awesome is that?! :D
So what lies further Now, that the results are out, the next phase is the Community Bonding period. During this period we are supposed to research more about our project, create milestones and think about the implementation details; do code reviews, present our project on coala mailing lists, and work out the schedule to follow in the 3 months of coding period; contact our mentors and discuss the project further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Proposal - Debugger for coala bears</title>
      <link>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-coala-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 18:15:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meetmangukiya.github.io/post/gsoc-coala-debugger/</guid>
      <description>I am applying for Google Summer of Code What is Google Summer of Code a.k.a. GSoC? Google Summer of Code is a platform to encourage students to work for Open Source. It is a 3 month internship-like program whereby student works with Open Source Organizations under the guidance of a mentor (who is usually a member of the organization) to write/modify programs/softwares for the organization.
What is coala? coala is a program that provides a unified interface to statically analyse any project through one application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>